Front end developer resume you can copy and use Jason M. Bourassa Front End Developer with a keen eye for detail

Details

4670 Garrett Street, 19108, Philadelphia, PA, US Tel 267-981-2091 jason@developer.com www.JasonMBou.com

Profile

Seasoned and independent Front End Developer with 5 years of experience in blending the art of design with skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging.

Very passionate about aesthetics and UI design.

Experience

Front End Developer at Henser Ltd., Philadelphia, PA Sep 2017 - currently employed

Deliver engaging user experience through optimization of images, code, and cross-browser compatibility, increasing Time on Page by +60 seconds for +50 websites

Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement

Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and Javascript.

Built single page applications (SPA), responsive web design, UI using HTML5 grid layouts, CSS3 media queries where its an expression and can be used to either true or false.

Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues

Front End Developer at Henser Ltd., Philadelphia, PA

Sep 2014 - Aug 2017

Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 19% faster load time than industry average

Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and

CSS3

Designing frontend within object-oriented Javascript frameworks like Angular.Js and Ext.Js.

Education

Associate in Computer Science at Saint Maria University,

Sep 2011 - Jul 2014

Graduated with the highest academy remarks.

Design & Coding

HTML, CSS

JavaScript, jQuery

Front End frameworks (Angular, Ember, React)

Responsive UI Design

WordPress

Adobe Photoshop

Visual Studio

Project Management

Jira

Slack

Trello

Languages

English

Native

Portuguese

Fluent

Spanish

Proficient